Guide to the Bill Dixon Papers MSS.481
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II. Bennington College, 1964-1995, 2005; 88.26 Linear Feet in 30 record cartons, 29 flat boxes, 16 manuscript boxes, 4 tall LP boxes, 1 oversize flat box, and 1 flat-file folder.; 40.26 Gigabytes in 42 digital files.
  - Subseries II.B: Performance and Event Recordings, 1964-1994; 50 Linear Feet in 26 record cartons, 19 flat boxes, 3 LP boxes, and 1 manuscript box
    - Black Music Concert, Robeson House, Undated; cuid38746 (Box 80, Half inch video reel 481_2662)
      Format: Sony CV; Duration: 56 minutes; Preservation Note: Video quality is poor. Video lighting is very dark.
    - Bill Dixon -- Reading Jack Moore's Retirement Narrative, Undated; cuid38745 (Box 28, Audiocassette 481_735)
    - Campus scenes -- trumpet playing, music building, Undated; cuid41224 (Box 65, Super 8mm film reel 481_1047)
      Color reversal; Silent.
    - Dance rehearsal, undated; cuid41267 (Box 80, Half inch video reel 481_2657)
      Format: EIAJ-1; Duration: 43 minutes; Preservation Note: Video quality is unstable. Video contains a great deal of black before the picture starts.
    - Event #3, Undated; cuid38750 (Box 53, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1306)
      Featuring "Jay, Jett, Steve, Hagen, Tift, etc."
    - Farewell Address at Bennington College, Undated; cuid38747
    - Jack Moore Retirement Piece, Undated; cuid38748 (Box 75, Vhs 481_2265)
    - Luz Fleming -- Senior Concert, and other Ensemble Recordings, Undated; cuid38744 (Box 27, Audiocassette 481_716)
    - Nadi Qamar performance, undated; cuid41266 (Box 80, Half inch video reel 481_2656)
      Format: EIAJ-1; Duration: 50 minutes; Preservation Note: Video lighting is very dark.
  - Subseries II.C. Teaching and Administrative Files, 1966-1995, 2005; 16.24 Linear Feet in 3 cartons, 15 manuscript boxes, 3 flat boxes, 1 oversize flat box, and 1 flat-file folder.
    Material pertaining to individual student records may be restricted in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Restricted materials are notated as such in the record's title. Please contact the Archives with specific questions regarding access to such records. All other materials are open to researchers.
    This subseries contains material related to Dixon's tenure as a professor at Bennington College, from 1968 to 1995, during which he also founded the Black Music Division (1974). Founding documentation of the Division includes reports, memos, and writings by Dixon. A report from the Black Music Division Visiting Committee dating from 1979 to 1981 provides an overview of the Division and their findings. Division meeting material in this subseries includes audio recordings, minutes, and notes. Dixon's administrative files contain budgets, correspondence, and memos related to the Division. Lecture notes, syllabi, recording transcripts, along with reading and listening lists for Dixon's classes and music lessons are in this subseries. Black Music Division Ensemble and other Bennington College event ephemera and planning files contain programs, promotional posters, correspondence, and notes. Work files for the Black Music Division's short-lived journal, Manuscript: Journal of the New Black Music, contain meeting minutes, writing submissions, correspondence, drafts, and mock-ups from 1974 to 1975. This subseries contains images of rehearsals, performances, college buildings, Bill Dixon, and fellow professors Stephen Horenstein, Sonny Brown, Arthur Brooks, and Nadi Qamar interacting with students. This subseries also contains completed questionnaires, most likely distributed by Dixon to faculty, students, and administrators, to test their knowledge of Black Music from the mid-1940s to the 1970s.
    - Meetings -- Preparation for Spring Music Festival, November 16, 1966; cuid38751 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1380)
    - Meetings -- A Compilation, 1970-1981; cuid38752 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2644)
    - Meetings -- Dance Division Meeting, December 14, 1972; cuid38753 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2625)
    - Meetings -- Black Music Festival Meeting, circa 1973; cuid38754 (Box 53, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1292)
    - Meetings -- Faculty Educational Policies Committee Meeting re: Proposal, Black Music Becoming a Division at Bennington College, 1973; cuid38755 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2622, 481_2626)
    - Meetings -- Black Music Division Meeting, April, 1973; cuid38756 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2639)
    - Meetings -- Black Music Meeting with Bill Dixon, Judith Dunn, Peter Lakowski, and Joanne Galli, April, 1973; cuid38757 (Box 54, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1331)
    - Meetings -- CAASV Community Forum, circa 1973-1980
      Includes a discussion about Bill Dixon's rehire, with faculty and student representatives present.
      - Part one, cuid40112 (Box 71, Half inch video reel 481_1793)
      - Part two, cuid40111 (Box 71, Half inch video reel 481_1788)
    - Meetings -- Black Music Division Meetings -- Minutes, Notes, Memos, 1973-1986; cuid40080 (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Meetings -- Black Music Division Meeting, Fall, 1975; cuid38758 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2620)
    - Meetings -- Black Music Division Meeting, Fall, 1975; cuid38759 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2634)
    - Meetings -- Faculty Educational Policies Committee and Bill Dixon Meeting, May 19, 1975; cuid38760 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2623)
    - Meetings -- Faculty Meeting, November 19, 1975; cuid38761 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2630)
    - Meetings -- Black Music Division Meeting, September 20, 1977; cuid38762 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2646)
    - Meetings -- Black Music Division Meeting, 1978; cuid38763 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2628)
    - Meetings -- Faculty meeting about tenure challenge, undated; cuid41263 (Box 80, Half inch video reel 481_2667)
      Format: EIAJ-1; Duration: 27 minutes; Preservation Note: Video lighting is very dark.
    - RESTRICTED: Meetings -- Administrative Talk, 1978; cuid38764 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_072)
      Note on tape label: "All is admin talk - Bill Dixon as Division head speaking with Shayne and Kevin Campbell as teaching assistants, (some text is illegible)"
    - Meetings -- Barrow, Bill Dixon, Stephen Horenstein Meeting Re: Curriculum, Introduction to Black Music I, March, 1978; cuid38765 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2642)
    - Meetings -- Black Music Faculty Meeting, Hoosick Falls, NY, March 5, 1978; cuid38766 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2637)
    - Meetings -- Black Music Division Meeting, March 15, 1978; cuid38767 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2633)
    - Meetings -- Black Music Division Meeting, March 29, 1978; cuid38768 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2651)
    - Meetings -- Black Music Division Meeting, Celina Davis Tutorial, April, 1978; cuid38769 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2647)
    - Meetings -- Black Music Division Meeting at Jennings Hall, Bennington College, April 26, 1978; cuid38770 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2621)
    - Meetings -- Milford Grace and Bill Dixon Re: Reappointment, May 2, 1978; cuid38771 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2641)
    - Meetings -- Faculty Roundtable, circa 1979; cuid38772 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2619)
    - Meetings -- Unknown Meeting, March 13, 1983; cuid38773 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2631, 481_2632)
    - Meetings -- Dance Division Meeting, September 27, 1983; cuid38774 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2649)
    - Meetings -- Meeting with Ann Berlanger, October 4, 1983; cuid38775 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2648)
    - Meetings -- Meeting Re: Guidelines for Black Music Division and Music Division to Meet, October 9, 1984; cuid38776 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2645)
    - Meetings -- Institute Discussion, Undated; cuid38777 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2650)
    - Meetings -- Jennings Hall Meeting with Arthur Brooks, Stephen Horenstein, Milford Graves, Undated; cuid38778 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2652)
    - Meetings -- Black Music Division Meeting, Undated; cuid38779 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2629)
    - Faculty ID and Library Cards, 1968-1985; cuid40321 (Box 170, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence and Memos, 1968-1995; cuid40081 (Box 139, Folder 6-8, Box 140, Folder 1-4, Box 141, Folder 1-5, Box 142)
    - Support Material and Evaluations Re: Retention of Bill Dixon as Bennington College Professor, 1970-1975; cuid40082 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Press Clippings, 1970s-1980s; cuid40083 (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - Black Music Division Founding and Support Material -- Proposals, History, Notes, Reports, 1972-1995; cuid40084 (Box 99, Folder 3-8)
    - Classes and Lectures -- Course Descriptions, Schedule Listings, Syllabi, Lecture Notes, Evaluations, Recording Transcripts, and Reading and Listening Lists, 1972-1995; cuid40085 (Box 136, Folder 12-13, Box 137, Folder 1-8, Box 138, Folder 1-11, Box 139, Folder 1-5, Box 210, Folder 10, 13)
    - Event Ephemera, 1972-1995; cuid40086 (Box 142, Folder 5-6, Box 143, Folder 1-3)
    - Event Ephemera -- Posters, 1973-1981, 1994; cuid40310 (Box 209, Folder 14, Box 210, Folder 9, Flat-file-folder 7)
    - Images -- Black Music Division and Dance Division Students and Faculty Rehearsing, Concerts, Classes, Portraits, Black Music Festival, Jennings Hall, Other Practice and Performance Spaces, 1972-1995; cuid40087 (Box 145, Folder 7-9, Box 146, Folder 1-13, Box 147, Folder 1-9, Box 209, Folder 11, 13)
    - Proposal for a Black Music Division at Bennington College -- Lecture / Letter Read by Bill Dixon, 1973; cuid38780 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2643)
    - "Four Early and Late Evenings of Sequences and Events in Black Music" -- Planning Notes, circa May 1973; cuid40314 (Box 210, Folder 11)
    - Black Music Festival -- Planning Notes, Meeting Minutes, Schedules, Programs, Images, 1973-1974, 1978; cuid38945 (Box 100, Folder 2, Box 209, Folder 12)
    - Paul Robeson House -- History, Memos, Notes, 1973-1986; cuid40088 (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Manuscript: Journal of the New Black Music -- Drafts, Meeting Minutes, Mock-up Issues, Notes, Issue One Work Files, Contributor Submissions and Correspondence, 1974-1975; cuid40089 (Box 143, Folder 4-8, Box 144, Folder 1-5, Box 145, Folder 1-6, Box 210, Folder 12)
    - Black Music Division Budget-Related Material, 1974-1990; cuid40090 (Box 136, Folder 2)
    - Dance Division -- Correspondence, Notes, Writings, 1974-1993; cuid40091 (Box 136, Folder 3)
    - Jazz Laboratory / Summer Program Re: Controversy -- Notes, Statements, Advertising, Memos / Communications, 1975-1976; cuid40092 (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Black Music Division Salary Lists, Positions, Student Statistics, 1975-1978, 1983, Undated; cuid40093 (Box 136, Folder 4)
    - Promotional Brochures, Class Catalogue Entries, and Related, 1976-1985; cuid40094 (Box 136, Folder 5, Box 209, Folder 10)
    - Faculty Record for Bill Dixon, 1977; cuid40095 (Box 136, Folder 6)
    - Black Music Division Newsletter, Issue One, 1979; cuid40096 (Box 136, Folder 7)
    - Black Music Division Visiting Committee -- Memos, Report, 1979-1981; cuid40097 (Box 136, Folder 8)
    - Black Music Division Secretary Position -- Memo and Notes, 1982; cuid40098 (Box 136, Folder 9)
    - Three Days in October, Commemorating October Revolution in Jazz -- Planning Material, October 5-7, 1994; cuid40099 (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Promotional -- Campus Advertisement with Bill Dixon, October 14, 2005; cuid38946
    - General Notes, To Do Lists, Undated; cuid40100 (Box 100, Folder 6-8, Box 136, Folder 1)
    - Black Music Division Five Year Plan, Undated; cuid40101 (Box 136, Folder 10)
    - Black Music Division Proposal for Contemporary Orchestra, Undated; cuid40102 (Box 136, Folder 11)
    - Contemporary Studies for Black Music from the Mid-1940s to the 1970s Completed Questionnaires, Undated; cuid40103 (Box 147, Folder 10-12)
    - Music Division's Statement Reflecting on the Musicianship and Character of Bill Dixon, Undated; cuid38781 (Box 46, Audiocassette 481_2653)
- Series III. Educational Programs and Appearances, 1959-2009; 42.37 Linear Feet in 16 record cartons, 14 flat boxes, 3 oversize flat boxes, and 3 manuscript boxes.; 14.2 Gigabytes in 49 digital files.
  This series includes material on the lectures, workshops, and programming that Dixon engaged in outside of his performing and teaching at Bennington College. Material includes audio and video recordings, and paper and digital files of lectures, workshops, and programming. Notable programs include Judson Arts Workshops and the University of the Streets. This series also includes images, event ephemera, and class lecture plans created during his visiting professorship at the University of Wisconsin, Madison from Fall 1971 to Spring 1972.
  This subseries is arranged chronologically, within groupings of files.
  - United Nations Jazz Society Panel Discussion, June, 1959; cuid38947
  - Funding Applications, Project Proposals, 1960s-1980s; cuid40104 (Box 148, Folder 1)
  - Bill Dixon Talks with Sun Ra, Summer, 1964; cuid8712 (Box 62, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2222)
    Housing annotations: "Conversation Part II with Joe Johnson and Jeanne Dixon"
  - Judson Arts Workshop, circa 1960; cuid38782 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1372)
  - Judson Arts Workshop, Judith Dunn's Loft, 1966; cuid38783 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1372)
  - Judson Arts Workshop Rehearsal, October 31, 1966; cuid38784 (Box 64, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1023)
  - Judson Arts Workshop, November 4, 1966; cuid38785 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1379)
  - Judson Arts Workshop -- Sunny Murray, Bill Dixon, and Judith Dunn, November 11, 1966; cuid40105
    - Audio (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1492)
    - Papers (Box 213, Folder 21)
  - University of the Streets Free Conservatory Orchestra Piece / Jay Adamson Voice Recording, 1967; cuid38786 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1374)
    Duration: 65 minutes; Preservation notes: Track 1: 7.5 ips, transfer OK; Track 2: 3.75 ips [Jay Adamson Voice Recording] significant speed issues, some digital correction applied to the access copy.
  - University of the Streets -- Large Orchestra Work, Summer, 1967; cuid38787 (Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2022, Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1542)
    Duration: 66 minutes
  - University of the Streets Free Conservatory Orchestra -- Orchestra Work, Summer, 1967; cuid38788 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1373)
  - University of the Streets, 1967; cuid38948
  - University of the Streets Free Conservatory Orchestra - Instruction and Rehearsal, 1967-1968; cuid8744 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2438)
  - University of the Streets Free Conservatory Orchestra, 1967-1968; cuid8714 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1362)
  - University of the Streets Free Conservatory Orchestra, 1967-1968; cuid8715 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1361)
  - University of the Streets -- Orchestra Piece, 1968; cuid38949
  - Event Ephemera, 1968-2006; cuid40106 (Box 148, Folder 2, Box 210, Folder 18)
  - Bill Dixon Orchestra Work at the Public Theatre, New York City, March, 1971; cuid38789 (Box 52, Quarter inch audio reel 481_420)
  - Visiting Professorship at University of Wisconsin, Madison -- Lecture Notes, Concert Ephemera, ID Cards, and Images of Practices, Rehearsals, Students, Classes, and Performances, Fall 1971-Spring 1972; cuid40107 (Box 148, Folder 3-13)
  - Visiting Professorship at University of Wisconsin, Madison -- Large Panel Images of Students in Practices, Rehearsals, Students, Classes, and Performances, Fall 1971-Spring 1972; cuid40108 (Box 150, Folder 1-5)
  - Visiting Professorship at University of Wisconsin, Madison -- Orchestral Work with Black Music Ensemble in Mills Hall, March 5, 1972; cuid8745 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2439)
  - Visiting Professorship at University of Wisconsin, Madison -- Orchestral Work with Black Music Ensemble in Mills Hall, March 5, 1972; cuid8746 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2440)
  - Visiting Professorship at University of Wisconsin, Madison -- First Orchestra Piece, circa 1971-1972; cuid38950
  - Visiting Professorship at University of Wisconsin, Madison -- Black Music Ensemble "Piece No. 3" Performance at Baraboo, May 1, 1972; cuid38017 (Box 51, Quarter inch audio reel 481_153)
  - Visiting Professorship at University of Wisconsin, Madison -- Dixon Speaking to Black Music Ensemble, April 16, 1972; cuid38792 (Box 53, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1304)
  - Visiting Professorship at University of Wisconsin, Madison -- Black Music Ensemble at Baraboo, May 3, 1972; cuid38019 (Box 51, Quarter inch audio reel 481_152)
  - Visiting Professorship at University of Wisconsin, Madison -- Black Music Ensemble Lecture and Demonstration, Mills Hall, March 5, 1972; cuid8720 (Box 14, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1104, Box 51, Quarter inch audio reel 481_157)
  - RESTRICTED: Visiting Professorship at University of Wisconsin, Madison -- "Appreciation" by RESTRICTED, Submitted for Class Assignment, 1972; cuid37972 (Box 63, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2340)
  - "Cheaters," University of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, December 14, 1971; cuid38790 (Box 53, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1295, Box 54, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1353)
  - Demonstration and Lecture at Thomas Jefferson School, Madison, Wisconsin, February 14, 1972; cuid38791 (Box 53, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1305)
    Featuring Bill Dixon, Jay Ash, John Hagen, Stephen Horenstein, and David Moss
  - Bill Dixon, Musician-Composer and Bennie Andrews, Painter-Writer at Queens College, New York City, circa 1973; cuid38793 (Box 31, Audiocassette 481_965)
  - Mt. Anthony Union High School Commencement Speaker -- Photograph and Press Clipping, June 15, 1973; cuid40109 (Box 149, Folder 1)
  - Bill Dixon Interviewed by Larry Neal at the Olitski House, Shaftsbury, Vermont, May 14, 1974
    - Tape one, cuid38794 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_570)
      Duration: 64 minutes.
    - Tape two, cuid38880 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_547)
    - Tape three, cuid38795 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_539)
      Duration: 53 minutes.
  - Boston Art Ensemble, May 30, 1974; cuid38796 (Box 53, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1310)
  - An Academy of Improvisation, Bill Dixon Talk Re: Contemporary Aspects of Improvisation, at Carnegie Hall, New York City, July 5, 1974; cuid38797 (Box 31, Audiocassette 481_949)
  - An Academy of Improvisation, Bill Dixon Talk Re: Contemporary Aspects of Improvisation, at Carnegie Hall, New York City -- Speech Text, Promotional Flier, July 5, 1974; cuid40110 (Box 149, Folder 2)
  - Compilation of Talks and Lectures, 1974-1987; cuid38798 (Box 32, Audiocassette 481_971)
  - Bill Dixon and Alan Silva Conversation, Winter 1976; cuid38799 (Box 23, Audiocassette 481_523, 481_524)
  - Interview with Art Brooks, Cynthia Kahlberg, Re: Aesthetics, 1976; cuid38800 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_491)
  - Bill Dixon and Alan Silva Conversation, 1977; cuid38801 (Box 23, Audiocassette 481_525)
  - Bill Dixon Lecture on the 1960s and the Jazz Composers Guild, circa 1978; cuid38802 (Box 31, Audiocassette 481_950)
  - Panel with Stanley Crouch, March 28, 1978; cuid38803 (Box 23, Audiocassette 481_520, 481_521, 481_522)
  - Ensemble Lecture and Demonstration at The Putney School, Putney, Vermont, April 21, 1978; cuid38804 (Box 22, Audiocassette 481_334)
  - Panel Discussion, May 24, 1978; cuid38805 (Box 31, Audiocassette 481_952)
  - Lecture on the Evolution of New Music, Jazz, Black Music, in Tallahassee, Florida, 1980; cuid38806 (Box 31, Audiocassette 481_951)
  - Compilation Tape -- Lecture in London; Performances in London, Paris, and Florence, Summer, 1980; cuid38807 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1548)
  - Lecture at Malcolm X House, Wesleyan University, October 28, 1983; cuid38808 (Box 32, Audiocassette 481_972)
  - Lecture at Alte Schmeide, Vienna, Austria, February, 1985; cuid38809 (Box 32, Audiocassette 481_976)
  - New Jazz Workshop with Bill Dixon, at the Museum of the 20th Century (Germany or Austria), February 4-9, 1985; cuid40113 (Box 149, Folder 3)
  - Lecture "Innovations and Innovators in American Music" at Southern Vermont College -- Speech Text, December 12, 1985; cuid40114 (Box 149, Folder 4)
  - 25 Years of the UNSRC Jazz Society Special Issue of "The World of Jazz" Booklet, 1985; cuid40115 (Box 149, Folder 5)
  - Bill Dixon Music Radio Show Schedules and Descriptions, 1985-1994; cuid40116 (Box 149, Folder 6)
  - Jazz Band Workshop at Middlebury College, 1986; cuid38810 (Box 31, Audiocassette 481_959)
  - SVC Teach-in, February 10, 1987; cuid38811 (Box 31, Audiocassette 481_957)
  - Workshop at Pori Ultra Music Meeting (1991); Speech at the End of Concert, Nicht Rot, Nicht Grün (1988), 1988, 1991; cuid38812 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2488)
  - "An Evening with Bill Dixon" at Community College of Vermont -- Event Ephemera, 1989-02-22; cuid40117 (Box 149, Folder 7)
  - Jerusalem Symposium -- Lecture to Ensemble, circa 1990; cuid38813 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1694)
  - Piano Workshop in Jerusalem, Israel, circa 1990; cuid38814 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1701)
  - Excerpts from Diallo, TU; Bill Dixon Discussion, circa 1990s; cuid38815 (Box 67, Vhs 481_020)
  - Bill Dixon Lecture with Chris Faris at Southern University College, March, 1990; cuid38816 (Box 69, Vhs 481_1084)
    Duration" 38 minutes
  - Poetry Reading, SVC, October 27, 1990; cuid38817 (Box 78, Vhs 481_2417)
  - Lecture at Southern Vermont College, March 4, 1991; cuid38818 (Box 31, Audiocassette 481_966)
  - Workshop at Pori Youth Center, July 19, 1991; cuid38819 (Box 32, Audiocassette 481_970)
  - Don Moore Interview, March 3, 1993; cuid38820 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_485)
  - University of the Streets -- Bill Dixon Radio, October 4, 1993; cuid38821 (Box 22, Audiocassette 481_347)
  - Lyon Masterclass in Lyon, France, circa 1992-1994
    - Video -- 1 of 2 (Box 67, Vhs 481_022)
    - Video -- 2 of 2, cuid38822 (Box 78, Vhs 481_2397)
  - Lecture and Masterclass in Villeurbanne, France, circa 1994; cuid38823 (Box 78, Vhs 481_2410)
  - Masterclass in France, November 7-8, 1994; cuid38824 (Box 31, Audiocassette 481_960, 481_961, 481_962)
  - Various Bill Dixon-related Events in Villeurbanne, France -- Event Ephemera, Notes, Correspondence, November 7-19, 1994; cuid40118 (Box 149, Folder 8)
  - Conférence Bill Dixon at Maison du Livre, de L'Image, et du Son, Lyon, France, November 9, 1994; cuid38825 (Box 32, Audiocassette 481_973)
  - The Peak of Perfection: Bill Dixon, Lithographs and Xylogravures at the Chittenden Bank, January, 1995; cuid38826 (Box 77, Vhs 481_2421)
  - University of the Streets, July 1, 1996
    Black and white; Silent.
    - Reversal original, cuid38827 (Box 65, 16mm film reels 481_1037)
      Preservation note: Some perforation damage throughout; long emulsion scratches in perforation area; sticky residue periodically in second half of reel; very overexposed portion late in reel.
    - Reversal print, cuid37637 (Box 66, 16mm film reels 481_977)
  - University of the Streets, August, 1996; cuid38828 (Box 69, Vhs 481_1068)
    Transferred from 16mm film
    Duration: 17 minutes
  - Lecture at New York University, New York, November 23, 1996; cuid38829
    - Audio (Box 32, Audiocassette 481_975)
    - Video (Box 67, Vhs 481_036)
  - Workshop at New York University, New York, November 23, 1996; cuid38830 (Box 67, Vhs 481_039)
    Duration: 125 minutes
  - NYU Ensemble at New York University, New York, November 23, 1996; cuid38831 (Box 27, Audiocassette 481_718, Box 48, Dat 481_2698, 481_2699, 481_2700, Box 45, Audiocassette 481_2575)
  - Masterclass at New York University, New York, November 23, 1996; cuid38832 (Box 28, Audiocassette 481_731, 481_732, Box 47, Audiocassette 481_2748)
  - NYU Avant-Garde Jazz Ensemble: University of the Streets at New York University, New York, December 13, 1996; cuid38833
    - Audio (Box 28, Audiocassette 481_742)
    - Video (Box 69, Vhs 481_1074)
  - Appearance and Interview at Sista's Place in Brooklyn, New York -- Agreement, Notes, Letters, November 21, 199; cuid40119 (Box 149, Folder 9)